Thomas Kiley

30 Arnold Road, Oxford, OX4 4BH

M: 07948284729 E: <u>hi@tkiley.co.uk</u> Portfolio: <u>www.tkiley.co.uk</u>

I am a team lead and a software engineer at Diffblue. I have 7 years of industry experience, including 2 years leading a team of four. I work with both stakeholders and my team to plan, prioritise and deliver features in line with a roadmap or to a release date. I write well-tested code, readable code in C++, Java, C# and Python. I have a 1st class honours degree in Discrete Mathematics from the University of Warwick.

Experience

Diffblue

Oct 2016 - Present

- Leading a cross-functional four-person team working on the core test generation engine.
- Delivered critical product features in C++, (based on the open-source CBMC) and in Java.
- Leading technical development of complex engineering tasks, including a modular "smart harness".
- Fixing bugs across the codebase, along with adding automated tests so the bug cannot reappear.
- Working with stakeholders including the product owner to understand requirements and making sure the engineering tickets solve the real user problem
- Tuned our code review process to ensure team members continuously learn from each other without getting bogged down in perfectionism.
- Actively promoting a culture of "if it isn't tested (in CI), it doesn't work".
- Running fortnightly "1-2-1s", setting quarterly goals and providing continuous feedback to team members so they were all able to grow.
- Handling various leadership responsibilities including running agile meetings, onboarding new team members and contributing to company road map planning.

In Mind Games

July 2014 - Oct 2016

- Sole programmer responsible for developing two games in Unreal Engine 4 in C++.
- Implemented an ocean simulation based on Gerstner Waves that featured a translucent ocean and a physics-driven buoyancy model.
- Prototyping a game in **C#** using **WinForms**.
- Working independently and remotely.

Born Ready Games

July 2012 - July 2013 (Intercalated Year)

- Released Strike Suit Zero http://store.steampowered.com/app/209540
- Gained one year of industry experience using **C++** within the context of the (in-house) game engine.
- Refactored the save system to support multiple save files.
- Bug fixing across the code base, including debugging Lua scripts, particularly in the run-up to launch.

doublesix games

September 2010 - January 2012 (Holiday Employment)

• Created some tools in **C#** for the in house engine including a level editor, a particle system editor and material designer similar to that found in Unreal Engine.

References are available upon request.

Education

| University of Warwick 2010 - 2014 | 1st Class Honours BSc in Discrete Mathematics with Intercalated Year Discrete Mathematics is a joint degree run by the Computer Science and Mathematics departments. | |
|--|---|--|
| Guildford County School 2003-2010 | A-Levels: | 2 A*s (Further Mathematics, Computing), 1 A (Mathematics), 1 B (Physics) |
| | AS-Levels: | 1 A (History) |
| | GCSEs: | 2 A* (Maths and Science), 5 As (including French) and 2 Bs |

Projects & Technologies

I have worked on a number of personal projects. These have included games, apps and tools. I've done these both **on my own**, and as part of a **team**. I have used a variety of tools and technologies, including **Android**, **Unity3D**, various **third party APIs** and **Google Cloud**.

You can read about some of the projects I have done at http://www.tkiley.co.uk or on my github profile at github.com/thk123

I am familiar with a wide range of tools, using them in both professional and hobby settings. I have used **CLion**, **Visual Studio**, **InteliJ** and other IDEs. I am familiar with several source control solutions, including **Perforce** and **Git**. I have used **JIRA** and **Trello** for project management. I am comfortable in both **Windows** and **Linux** environments. I have used a number of CI systems, in particular, **Travis**.

Other Interests

In my spare time, I organise and campaign for the Green Party. I also frequent StackOverflow (http://stackoverflow.com/users/958004/t-kiley) as I enjoy finding new problems and helping people solve them. I set up and help run a Code Club in our local library teaching children Scratch and Python.

I like to go cycling, seeing live music and playing board games.